Oh! Tani-kun!
Morning!
FREEZE...
Hey, we have a long homeroom today, right?
TRUDGE TRUDGE TRUDGE
Do you think we'll be talking about
our class trip? I can't wait!
Yeah, maybe.
Just the same as always.
Completely normal.
But I guess it would be.
That's how it works, right?
CLASS TRIP
OBJECTIVES
BROADEN
YOUR
EXPERIENCE
ABIDE BY THE RULES
OF LIVING IN A GROUP
STUDY
HISTORY
DAY 1
KYOTO
GROUP ACTIVITIES
NARA
DAY 2
DAY 3
OSAKA
So, that's the general schedule
I'd like to work with.
And groups will have free time,
so think about where you want to go.
I'll hand out the group
and room assignments later.
CLASS TRIP
OBJECTIVES
The Class Trip Arc begins now!
YOU AND I ARE POLAR OPPOSITES
CLASS TRIP GUIDE
YEAR 2 CLASS
KYOTO
Sorry, guys.
This should be class rep work.
EVERYONE IN THE
GOING-HOME CLUB
It'll go faster if we all pitch in, right?
I wanna ker-chack the mega stapler!
So sloppy!
KONEKO PREFECTURAL
HIGH SCHOOL
CLASS TRIP GUIDE
YEAR 2 CLASS
QUIET FOCUS...
DEAD-END
PIECE
Sorry for making you help me, Nisshi.
It's fine. I actually like
doing simple tasks like this.
You're so nice.
MUTTER MUTTER MUTTER
Seriously, when people say,
"I have club activities"?
It's treated like a perfect excuse,
but are clubs that special?
2-8 CLASS REPS
If you can't,
then don't be a class rep, right?
Is it just for your résumé?
I despise people who only seem
to have it together and skate by.
CRACKLE...
Behind their dazzling lives,
someone else is doing the work,
but no one pictures that, do they?
Hon-chan, calm down.
I'll put on a video of a funny
comedy I watched last night.
Then they slowly
turned around and said...
It was you!
HEE HEE...
I don't get it.
Hey, Nisshi, do you have
any recent fun stories?
Huh? What about the video?
Any progress since you said
you didn't know how you felt?
You and Yamada.
What?
JOLT
Um, that's... Well...
I think I probably—
You two are doing all that?
WAAAAAAH
Yamada!
Huh? What? Why?
Day 1
Day 2
Isn't it exhausting doing that
by yourselves?
We've got about eight of us working on it.
QUICK QUICK QUICK
That sounds like too many, doesn't it?
Yeah. I'm just an extra body.
Lolz.
Then, why don't you help us over here?
Leave it to me!
First, go ahead and fold all that paper.
Will do!
Hey, for the groups, should it be decided
by lottery, or should we get to pick?
It'd be better
if we got to pick, right?
Yeah, most people probably
feel that way.
Depending on how many
can be in a group,
I bet there'll be some awkward pairings.
Tani-kun, what do you think?
What?
Yeah.
What does "yeah" mean?
You weren't listening, were you?
What's with this vibe?
Are they in the middle of a fight?
How much of your trip do you
have planned in your class?
Aside from activities for the whole class.
Um, we've divided into groups,
and the groups are deciding where to go.
Oh. Then you've gotten farther than us.
Really?
Nisshi is able to talk more than before.
They've got a nice atmosphere going.
Keep it up, Nisshi!
Just consider me invisible right now.
SHFF...
Gapacho said they're already
discussing their class recreation stuff.
Really? That's so quick!
Hon-chan, help me!
THUD THUD THUD THUD
Please don't enter
an I-know-nothing, I-don't-exist zone!
"I AM JUST BACKGROUND" MODE
THUD THUD
I seem to be holding
a conversation somehow,
but I feel my pulse in my ears!
I think I'm going crazy!
I'm pretty sure I'm happy,
but I still want this time to go faster!
FWIP FWIP FWIP
CONTRADICTORY
We're done!
The two of you work so fast it's freaky.
Well, I'll drop these off
in the staff room.
SHFF...
Want me to carry them?
It's fine. Just sit there. Forever.
Don't make it so I can't get up.
Hon-chan!
I need something... to talk about.
The wind ensemble sure is
practicing hard, huh?
The sun has been
setting earlier lately, hasn't it?
Right?
So, um...
The group activity for our class trip...
Nishi-san, when your group decides where
you're going, will you tell me in secret?
What?
I should ask why or what for.
No.
IT'S NOT LIKE I HAVE ABSOLUTELY NO IDEA
I can't do that.
I should be honest. Honest.
I-I understand and will do so.
That's crazy polite.
Huh? Where's Yamada?
He left with everyone from his class.
Oh, dear. I'm sorry.
You didn't have to wait.
You could've left with him.
No, I'm already over capacity.
Oh, you're shrinking.
I guess it's certain, then.
Yes.
Yamada, where were you?
I went and helped next door.
Yeah?
Today, I'm the only one who's been
weirdly self-conscious. I'm a disgrace.
You know...
before a class trip,
the number of couples increases, right?
What? Really?
I guess it's to take full advantage
of the free time.
Phrasing.
Suzuki, Tani-kun,
what're you going to do?
What?!
Uh, yeah, what should we do?
AWKWARD
What? Suzuki, are you still acting
like that with Tani-kun?
Huh? What? Acting like what, exactly?
Highly suspiciously.
Sus—
Today just happens to be
that sort of day, that's all!
What kind of day is that?
I'm usually more clever than this!
Tani-kun is laughing, though.
Hey.
Sorry.
Suzuki-san, I'd like to spend my
free time with you.
Sudden!
Wow! Well said, Tani!
Okay.
I'm so happy for you.
Yes, please go right ahead.
TRAIN-TO-SCHOOL GROUP
Did Suzuki and Tani
seem kind of weird today?
Huh? Did they?
Well, as long as they don't say anything,
we can leave it alone, right?
Yeah, I guess so.
Huh? Are we going to
head home together like this?
I'm gonna stop by the convenience store.
Huh? Sure.
Well, then...
Nice! What should I buy?
Seriously?
Azuma!
Hey! Morning!
Kawasaki! Morning.
Did your group decide
where to go during the class trip?
No. We haven't even decided
on our groups yet.
What? This late?
We decided a whole bunch of stuff.
It's exhausting.
The whole class has a
"I don't wanna say the wrong thing" aura,
so no one gives a single opinion.
CLASS TRIP
PICKING GROUPS
Huh? Then we'll decide the groups
by lottery. Is that okay?
Okay, we'll do it by lottery.
Is there anywhere you wanna go?
Nah.
Well, no. Nowhere in particular.
I'm begging you!
Please give your opinion just a bit!
And then they say that
I decided everything behind their backs!
Don't skip making decisions
or giving your opinion, then!
C-Calm down. Calm down.
ARGHHHH
You did good work.
Hey, should we assign groups
by lottery, or let everyone pick?
It'd be better
if we got to pick, right?
To be honest, I think
a lottery is way better.
So, I fumbled planning the class trip,
so we're going to decide stuff fast now.
I knew it! I thought our class
seemed way behind!
First, form groups of two to
three of all girls or all boys.
Then we'll combine each boy group with a
girl group to form a group of five to six.
How slapdash can you be?
Uh-oh. Two to three people.
HANG OUT A LOT
HANG-OUT GROUP
(+SUZUKI)
ALWAYS TOGETHER
What should I do?
Is there anyone left over?
GLANCE GLANCE GLANCE
(I'LL GO TO A DIFFERENT GROUP)
(GOT IT!)
Did she understand?
DID SHE UNDERSTAND...?
Teacher! Can we have a group of four?
No! That's not it!
Huh? Sure.
That easy?
Just talk it out amongst yourselves
and make it work.
IF IT GETS DONE,
ANYTHING'S FINE.
IN THE END...
In the end...
Yay!
YAY!
SIGH...
The truth is, I've already
bought sightseeing magazines.
TABIPPLE
FALL
BAM
Wow! Well done!
FWIP FWIP FWIP
I'm glad I didn't have to be
awkwardly considerate.
...HUH?
No, no, no.
If I worry about every little thing
the whole trip, what'll happen?
Since I started high school,
it's like I'm in a group, but also not.
I make sure not to get too attached, so I
can go anywhere, and I keep my distance.
It's easiest when it's just me,
or me and one other person.
Still, maybe my social circle
is too small?
YEAR 1, SPRING
Nice to meet you!
What middle school are you from?
1. KAWASAKI
YEAR 2, SPRING
2. SUZUKI
Hey!
It's not that I'm shy around strangers,
but for some reason, I tend
to get cautious at weird times.
And yet it's so easy
to pester Taira for no reason.
Don't pester me for no reason.
Where's this coming from?
I was just saying, "Taira is
so easy to talk to." That's all.
What?
Well, of course I am,
from your perspective.
What?
There's no reason for you
to be nervous, right?
Huh?
Like, "What if I say this?"
Or, "I want to look good here."
Worrying about stuff
like status and feelings
versus it not affecting anything
if you mess up...
the comfort level is different.
Not that I know if you
worry about that stuff, though.
Wait, what?
That means...
Taira, it's as if I totally
look down on you!
That's because that's the truth!
Oh, but when I think about it...
CLASS TRIP
PICKING GROUPS
SILENCE...
SENSE OF ANXIETY
TABIPPLE
FALL
NO SENSE OF ANXIETY
That could explain it.
Is that so?
Oh, not the looking down on you thing.
Anxiety.
About what?
Well, I have work today, so...
Sure! Work hard!
I wonder...
what am I afraid of?
Azuma!
Are you free on Saturday?
Oh.
What are you guys talking about?
Just asking her
to hang out on Saturday.
What? I'll totally go!
Azuma, you can go, right?
I'm interested in that guy.
Will you help me?
Sure.
Azuma, you know I like him, right?
Let's help her out.
We're friends, right?
I guess it's fine.
It's not like I hate them.
Being used... and getting swept along,
even though I know what's going on.
If that's true...
that has nothing to do with now, does it?
Back then, I think I had even less of my
own thoughts and will than I do now.
Don't skip making decisions
or giving your opinion, then!
You're so right, Kawasaki.
Hey! Azuma!
Yoohoo! Good work today!
Nabesato, this isn't
the way you go home, is it?
Yeah. We thought we'd go shopping,
maybe get a few things for the class trip.
We're headed the same way,
so can we walk together?
Yeah.
I don't go this way much,
so it feels brand new.
Hey, I heard a taiyaki shop opened up in
front of the station. Let's stop by later.
Didn't you just eat a snack?
Isn't there a second stomach for taiyaki?
I've never heard that.
Can I go shopping with you?
Yes! There it is!
We're going to a drugstore.
Is there one you like?
We're thinking of going
to the one by the statue.
The one by the station's
south entrance is well stocked.
Oh.
I want to buy face wash
and moisturizer for a travel kit.
Azuma, do you know of any good ones?
Maybe buy containers
and fill them with your stuff?
Oh, good idea.
TEA
FOR SALE AT THE HOTEL SHOP
Maybe they'll have
some where we stay?
Really?
And this is the first chance we've had to
see Azuma without makeup! I can't wait!
I'm a little curious, too.
It's not like there's no difference,
but it's not enough to get a laugh,
so don't get too excited.
What's that mean?
TAIYAKI
What?
It looks like they're eating taiyaki!
I'm so jealous!
O D E N
Go home.
Class trip!
Class trip, day 1: Hands-on learning!
DAY 1: HANDS-ON LEARNING
EVERYONE SPLITS UP TO TAKE
THE COURSE THEY CHOSE
PAINTING 1
PAINTING 2
TRIP GUIDE
MAKING
JAPANESE
SWEETS
CERAMICS
KUMIHIMO BRAIDING
All right, everyone gather up
for each activity separately!
I wish I could've done Japanese
sweets instead of ceramics.
CERAMICS GROUP
PAINTING GROUP
Isn't something you can keep better?
JAPANESE SWEETS
GROUP
We got the Japanese sweets
experience through R-P-S!
We'll eat enough for our
fallen comrades!
Don't kill me off!
You can only eat what you've made.
Oh! Nissan!
JAPANESE SWEETS
MAKING VENUE
Suzuki-san.
The pretty girl! Yamada's friend!
The unrealistic couple
Nisshi told me about.
Is it okay if we sit here?
Please do.
N-Nice to meet you.
Sorry for intruding on your table.
SMILE
(NEUTRAL ATTITUDE)
Nice to meet you.
Oh! She's adorable!
Hurry up and sit down.
What an amusing woman.
You take this and go like this...
The teacher makes it
look so easy, but this is hard.
Tani-kun, you're so good!
Did you practice in secret?
Of course I didn't.
Then why can you do it?
What?
"Why? I'm just doing it how I was shown."
He's that kind of character, huh?
What was that?
Oh, sorry. It slipped out a little.
Oh, right! Nissan, where is
your group going tomorrow?
I think it's...
in that order. Right, Hon-chan?
Yeah.
That's pretty much the same as us!
We might end up
in the same place!
Hang on.
How about here?
I want to go! I'm in! I'm in!
Sounds good.
No objections!
Then it's decided!
All right!
Th-That guy...
He arranged it around Nissan, right?
GRIN...
If we see each other,
I'd love to take a picture!
What? Um, I'd love to!
I'D LOVE
TO...!!!!
BIG ROOM
If the baths start with group 1,
then group 7 is way later, right?
Want to play cards while we wait?
Oh! I love the classics.
It has to be, right? But still...
I brought dominoes, too.
Right?
Now that's unusual.
Hey, Suzuki?
Yeah?
Suzuki, are you and Tani dating?
What?!
Yes, but...
Huh? Now?
The two of them are always together,
but I guess this is how people see them.
We were wondering which it was.
When Suzuki is with a guy,
there's no special meaning, right?
EXAMPLE
Really?!
SQUEE SQUEE
YAY YAY
Wow, which one of you confessed first?
What sparked it?
Do you actually talk to each other?
I totally get it. You just want to
press her with lots of questions.
How nostalgic.
She's acting like a veteran.
How far have you gone?
Wha?!
Oh, you're really going for it, huh?
When they called you two at the
culture festival, what were you doing?
And also...
Does Tani even have that kind of desire?
Honestly! We're closed for business!
Oh, dear. She's closed.
How far?
Those things that everyone's
excitedly imagining...
Not a single one has happened!
Group 7! Head to the baths.
When I really think about it,
up to this point...
I may have been pressing him a lot.
I WOULD LIKE
TO HUG...
STARE...
But he'll take my hand and stuff, so...
BA-DUMP
If I'm totally honest,
I want him to start stuff even more!
When Suzuki is with a guy,
there's no special meaning, right?
Was I putting out too much of a
"non-romantic character" vibe?
Oh! Suzuki!
Here you are.
Azu...
Why the troubled expression?
I want there to be developments.
Oh, my!
I guess... I want that kind of appeal.
GURGLE
Suzuki, you're more than cute enough.
Azu, this "cute" of yours
isn't how I want to be thought of.
NOT DENYING IT
But... I mean, it's not something
you should rush into in a panic.
I mean, the peak
is everything that leads up to it.
So, slow is fine, isn't it?
Really? But...
GURGLE
I mean, I'd at least like to
smooch sometime soon.
Smooch.
SMOOCH...
Do you think I could... you know, give
off a "good woman" vibe like you do?
I mean, if I had to say,
I'm more the "nobody really cares woman."
I'M NOT A
GOOD EXAMPLE...
She's blinding. Someone save me.
You were smart to bring a hair dryer.
Oh. Azuma, your eyebrows
seem kinda different.
Oh, with this lustrous, flowing hair
and fresh-out-of-the-bath appearance,
I do hope I see Tani-kun!
You can't wait until morning?
It'll be over in a few minutes.
Can't I just run into him at the entrance?
TINTED
I want him to see the natural me,
right out of the bath!
COLORED LIP BALM
MINERAL
FOUNDATION
Even though it's a fake no-makeup face?
Don't look!
SNEAK...
Why are you the embarrassed ones?
It's totally fine to be introverted.
You're going to make fun.
Huh? Where's Tani-kun?
This is the key,
so he should be there, right?
Yoohoo.
Yamada said you'd probably be over here.
THUMP
Hey, I'm a little different
than usual, aren't I?
Yes. My heart skipped a beat.
THUMP THUMP THUMP
A perfect score? Suddenly,
the solution I wanted has arrived.
I thought you were someone else,
so I was surprised.
No, I had it wrong! It was fear!
OH NO...!!
But it was you, Suzuki-san,
so I felt better.
I see.
Oh, right!
CHANGING THE SUBJECT
TO HIDE EMBARRASSMENT
Tani-kun, you ended up in a big room
with a bunch of noisy people.
Are you okay? It's kind of hilarious.
Don't find hilarity in this.
They seemed to be having fun
playing a card game.
Did you join in?
I didn't know the rules,
so I just watched.
Sounds like fun!
That goofy way guys get excited.
But not long ago, you probably
would've turned away from all of it.
Both the room and the game.
That's not...
That's probably true.
That's right.
It is true.
Spending so much time
with other people like this...
A year ago, I'd never have
imagined myself doing it.
Which way is more fun?
I don't think it's about
which is more fun.
Oh?
OH...?
I never felt particularly
dissatisfied with anything.
No, but that's the part of Tani-kun
I fell in love with in the first place.
SOLITARY
It's just...
now I have confusion and worries
that I didn't have when I was alone.
And things I wouldn't have
known otherwise.
There are probably still a lot more.
I'm glad that I'm not
still ignorant of those things.
So, it's not "which one," it's "both"?
Yeah. And that's why...
I'm glad I met you.
Ta— Yuu— Tani-kun!
U-Up until just now,
I was only thinking of wicked things!
I'm so embarrassed!
Yuusuke-kun...
I love you.
Miyu...
Okay! Time to get back
to our rooms, right?!
See you tomorrow!
Have fun in that room of yours!
There's no need to get weirdly panicked!
And so...
they stayed up long
into the night of their first day.
Yay! Yay!
I'm looking forward to tomorrow!